So, this is my complete get_batches code that generates mini-batches of data.
这是我完成的 get_batches 代码 它会生成迷你批次的数据
So, the first thing I wanted to do here is get
首先
the total number of complete batches that we can make in batches.
我想获取能够获得的总批次数量 n_batches
To do that, I first calculated how many characters were in a complete mini-batch.
第一步是计算一个完整的迷你批次中有多少个字符
So, in one mini-batch,
在一个迷你批次中
there's going to be batch size times sequence length number of characters.
字符数量是 batch_size * seq_length
Then, the number of complete batches that we can make is
我们能够创建的总批次数量是
just the length of the array divided by the total number of characters in a mini-batch.
数组长度除以单个迷你批次中的字符数
This double slash is an integer division
这个双斜杠表示整数除法
which we'll just round down any decimal leftover from this division.
它会对除法结果向下舍入
With that, we have the number of completely full batches that we can make.
这样就获得了能够创建的总批次数量
Then, we get our array and we take all the characters in
然后获取数组并从该数组中拿出
the array up to n_batches times this total character size for a mini-batch.
直到 n_batches * batch_size_total 个字符前的字符
So here, we're making sure that we're keeping
在这里确保仅保留
only enough characters to make full batches,
足够创建完整批次所需的字符
and we may lose some characters here.
我们可能会丢失一些字符
But in general, you're going to have enough data that getting rid
但是通常数据都足够多
of a last unfold batch is not really going to matter.
删除最后一个不完整的批次影响不大
Next, with reshaping, we can take our array and we
接下来 对于 reshape()
can make the number of rows equal to our batch size,
我们可以获取数组并使行数等于 batch_size
and that's just how many sequences we want to include in a mini-batch.
表示我们希望在一个迷你批次中包含的序列数量
So, we just say we want the number of rows
我们希望行数等于 batch_size
to be batch size and then we put this negative one.
然后在这里传入 -1
Negative one here is kind of a dimension placeholder,
-1 是一种维度占位符
and it'll just automatically fill up the second dimension
它将自动填充第二个维度
to whatever size it needs to be to accommodate all the data.
从而包含所有数据
Then finally, I'm iterating over my batch data using a window of length sequence length.
最后 使用长度为 seq_length 的窗口遍历批次数据
So here, I'm taking in a reshaped complete array and then looking at all our rows,
在这里接受变形后的完整数组 然后查看所有行（所有批次）
all our batches, and the columns are in a range from n to n plus sequence length,
列数范围是从 n 到 n+seq_length
which makes our sequence length window.
表示长度为 seq_length 的窗口
This completes x our input mini-batch.
这样就获得了输入迷你批次 x
Then, what I did here for the target y is I just
然后对于目标 y
initialized an array of all zeros that's the same shape as x,
将数组中的值全初始化为零 并且形状和 x 一样
and I just kind of fill it up with values from our x array shifted by one.
然后用 x 数组中的值填充该数组并且偏移一个位置
From the start to the end,
从到到尾
I just shifted over x by one.
使 x 偏移一个位置
Then in the case of reaching the very end of our array,
如果抵达数组的末尾
I'm going to make the last element of y equal to the first element in our array.
则使 y 的最后一个元素等于该数组中的第一个元素
I'm not super sure why most people do it this way,
很多人喜欢将数组前后连起来
wrapping our array around so that the last element of y is the first element of x.
使 y 的最后一个元素等于 x 的第一个元素 我不太确定为何这么做
But I've seen this many times,
但是我多次见到这种做法
and so I did it in the cyclical way and it
所以我也这么循环
seems like the network trains perfectly fine doing this.
似乎网络训练效果很好
So, it does not seem to be a problem.
所以这么做不成问题
The main thing is we want x and y to be the same size.
我们的目标是希望 x 和 y 是一样形状的
So, if you did this right and you want to test your implementation,
如果你的代码正确并且想要测试代码
you should have gotten batches that looks something like this.
你的批次数据应该看起来这样
Right here, we have a batch size of eight,
批次大小是 8
so you have eight rows here,
所以这里有 8 行
and then we're just printing out the first 10 items in a sequence.
我们按顺序输出前 10 项
So, you should see 10 items here.
所以这里应该有 10 项
The important thing to note here is that you want to make sure that the elements in x,
最重要的是确保 x 中的元素
like the actual encoded values,
即实际编码值
are shifted over by one in y.
在 y 中向右偏移一个位置
So, we have 51 as the first item here and as the zeroth item here,
所以 51 在这里是第 1 项 在这里是第 0 项
then 23 and 23.
然后是 23 和 23
Likewise, 55 is here and 55 is here in y. I
同理 55 在这里 然后在 y 中 55 在这里我希望
basically want to make sure that everything is shifted
所有值都正确偏移
over correctly, and this looks good.
看起来没问题
So now that we have our batch data,
获得批次数据后
the next step we'll talk about is actually building the network.
下一步我们将讨论如何实际构建网络